Hello everyone and welcome to English Pot.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and
today English Pot is in the kitchen.
That's right, today we are going to hit
the kitchen and we're going to bake a cake.
Alright, so check out this dialogue first.
When we come back
we'll be talking about some
very key phrases and
words for cooking in English.
Okay, so are you ready to
learn how to bake a cake?
Almost. Let me just put my apron on.
Okay, so the first thing we're
going to do is preheat the oven.
That way we have it at the desired temperature
once we finish preparing everything.
Set it to 375 degrees Fahrenheit.
Got it!
Now we're going to make the batter.
Take some butter and sugar and mix it
lightly until you have a nice consistency.
Then add some vanilla extract
and eggs and continue mixing.
Do I have to use the whisk
or can I use the electric mixer?
Go ahead and use the mixer
but put it on medium speed.
I'm going to sift the flour and
baking powder separately and
then we can mix it with milk
and the rest of the ingredients.
Okay, so now we need a baking pan, right?
Yeah, but grease and flour at first so
the cake won't stick to it when it bakes.
Done!
So how long do we bake it for?
We can leave it in there
for about 25 minutes.
Then we let it cool for 10 minutes
before we remove the cake from the pan.
Wow, this is a lot easier than I thought.
All right, we're back.
So now let's take a look at some of
those key words on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Well, first of all, we
have a special thing to
keep our clothes clean
while we are cooking.
And what is this thing called Marco?
This is called an apron, an apron.
So it's not actually a shirt, it's a piece
of fabric that you maybe tie around your
waist or around your neck to protect
your clothes from flour and butter and oil.
That's right, so it's very common to wear
an apron while you're cooking or maybe while
you're cleaning the house or the kitchen in
order to avoid getting dirty like you say.
And so we're going to start baking
our cake and the first thing that we
do is we turn on the oven in order
to have it at the desired temperature.
Now this is something
you might see in a recipe.
It says the desired
temperature is 450 degrees.
So that means the
temperature you want to achieve.
Maybe when you turn the
oven on, it's only 100 degrees.
So you have to wait for
the desired temperature,
which is what is
indicated in the recipe.
That's right.
So this is what we want, we want the
desired temperature of 375 degrees.
And so now we got that done and
now we're going to make the batter.
All right, the batter is the liquid.
It's the cake before the
cake becomes a cake.
So it's usually like a
very thick liquid, like
a very thick, almost
buttery, milky substance.
And after you cook it, it turns hard.
So batter is the liquid form.
Right.
So when you're making
a cake, you make batter.
Now it's different because
if you're making pizza
or you're making bread,
it's not called batter.
Now if you're making pizza or bread because
those are thicker, they're called dough.
But when it's still
like milk, you know, or
water, it's like a liquid,
we call it a batter.
A batter, very good.
So obviously to make the batter, we
add sugar, we add butter, we add eggs.
And then what we want
to do is we want to mix it.
And so the other person
asks, well, what do I do?
Do I have to use a
whisk or an electric mixer?
All right, these are two very important
tools that you will find in most kitchens.
A whisk is like a spoon, but it's
made of metal and it's empty inside.
And we use it for things
like eggs or milk and sugar.
And it can go very, very quickly.
It makes it, yeah, it's like a whisk sound.
Like wire all around it.
Yeah, it's wire that's woven together.
And so it's a very, very handy tool,
but you only use one hand to use it.
But an electric mixer
is what the name says.
It's electric, you plug it in, and it
does the whisking automatically.
That's right.
All right, so this is what we want to use.
And before we put the batter into
the baking pan, what we want to do
first is we want to grease and
flower the sides of the baking pan.
So then, you know, it won't stick.
All right, so to grease something
means to use oil or butter
to make sure that the meat or
the dough does not stick later.
That's right.
So you can even use it for, obviously, in cooking terms,
if you put butter or something like this, but even
grease like the black grease, maybe you need to put it
in your door because maybe it's making that weird sound.
So to grease something is
to add oil or to add butter
in order to, you know, keep
something from sticking.
That's right.
Okay, so a lot of words there now,
why don't we pass on to some phrases.
Let's start with some fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
Now, at the beginning of the
dialogue, we talked about the oven.
The real phrase you're going to
see in a cookbook is preheat the oven.
That's right. So we have the prefix
there pre to preheat something.
And that means to
begin or to start heating.
Now, this is because when I turn my oven
on, right, Marco, it's not 450 degrees.
Mm-hmm.
It takes some time to become hot.
So we preheat the oven and
we turn it on before we need
it in order to make sure it's
ready when we do need it.
That's right.
So you're going to see
it in every recipe if you're
baking something, you
need to preheat the oven.
And now when we were
actually mixing some of the things,
we came up on this
interesting phrase when we said,
we need to sift the flour
and the baking powder.
All right.
Now, these are both white substances.
They're soft.
Mm-hmm.
They're dry.
And sometimes they are, they're bumpy.
They have lumps in them.
So we need to make sure
that there are no lumps.
And we have a special
tool that will help us
sift the flour and sift
the baking powder.
So it's like a wire mesh tool
and you rotate the handle.
You turn the handle and it will flatten out
this flour so that there are no more bumps.
It's all smooth.
Okay.
I think I've heard it also when
they're talking about gold, right?
Don't they say that they were
sifting for gold in the rivers?
That's right.
Well, you have a tray and
you shake the tray to make sure
the small gold falls down, but
the big, the chunks stand top.
That's the same idea, yeah.
Okay.
So that's what we're doing here.
We're sifting the flour
and the baking powder.
And now we put our cake in the oven and
we ask, well, so how long do we bake it for
and we say, well, we can leave
it in there for about 25 minutes.
So the phrase here to leave it in
means to keep the cake in the oven.
And this is something we
can say about a lot of things.
So maybe the turkey that
we're cooking is in the oven.
It's been in the oven for four hours and
I look at it and I say, is it ready yet?
My mom says, no, leave it in.
Leave it in.
Yeah.
So that means don't take it out.
Keep it in the oven.
Leave it in.
So we don't really need
to say leave it inside
the oven or we don't
need to be too specific.
We can just say leave it in.
Keep it cooking.
That's right.
Okay.
So let's listen to our
dialogue one last time.
Okay.
So are you ready to
learn how to bake a cake?
Almost.
Let me just put my apron on.
Okay.
So the first thing we're going
to do is preheat the oven.
That way we have it at the desired temperature
once we finish preparing everything.
Set it to 375 degrees Fahrenheit.
Got it.
Now we're going to make the batter.
Take some butter and sugar and mix it
lightly until you have a nice consistency.
Then add some vanilla extract
and eggs and continue mixing.
Do I have to use the whisk
or can I use the electric mixer?
Go ahead and use the mixer,
put it on medium speed.
I'm going to sift the
flour and baking powder
separately and then we can mix it
with milk and the rest of the ingredients.
Okay.
So now we need a baking pan, right?
Yeah.
But grease and flour at first so the
cake won't stick to it when it bakes.
Done.
So how long do we bake it for?
We can leave it in there
for about 25 minutes.
Then we let it cool for 10 minutes
before we remove the cake from the pan.
Wow.
This is a lot easier than I thought.
So baking a cake seems easy enough.
Now maybe there are some other things
that we can add that we didn't mention.
Like, for example, vanilla extract.
It's mentioned in the recipe.
So that is what is this?
It's like a liquid, right?
It's a liquid.
It's a flavor.
And so extracts are used to
give different foods, flavors.
You can have orange
extract and vanilla extract.
And vanilla is actually, vanilla
comes from a bean, a brown bean.
And they take the oil from this plant.
And that's what gives things
like cake of vanilla flavor.
And now what about this baking pan?
This is specifically for cakes.
Now what if you're making something
like muffins or something like that?
Is it also called like a baking pan?
No, you'd have a muffin
tin or a muffin pan, yeah.
And so those are different shapes.
They're round.
They're circular.
They're made of that tin material.
So they're not very heavy.
And they can go in the oven and not break.
But normally we have a
baking sheet, which is flat.
Or a baking pan, which
would be for cake pan.
It's not like that.
It's got sides on it.
Right.
And we have a muffin
tin, which is for muffins.
And well, what we didn't mention
is we actually have our cake,
but then there's
something that we always
add on top of the
cake or all over the cake.
Yeah, well, not always, but most cakes,
at least most tasty cakes have frosting.
So that's something that you add
after the cake has finished cooking.
And that's right.
So frosting is like a cream or
something that you add around the cake.
Actually, just sugar.
Just sugar.
Sugar and water.
Really.
You can add milk if you
want to make it thicker.
But when I make frosting, I
like to make it from scratch.
That means I make it by myself.
I use water and powdered sugar.
Powder sugar.
And then you mix it.
You whisk it.
And then you get the frosting.
Exactly.
Very interesting.
Well, maybe this
recipe is actually real,
although we didn't give
the amounts to quantities.
But maybe you can try baking a
cake and let us know how it goes.
Or maybe you can give us a cake recipe.
That's right.
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
We hope to see you guys there.
Bye.